Joshua A. Leath

PROFILE

I am a software engineer with multiple years of experience with JavaScript, Ruby, Go and various frameworks. I am a cocreator of Chimera \mathscr{D} , an open-source tool for automating canary deployments of containerized microservices.

SKILLS

Languages

JavaScript, Ruby, Go

Cloud

AWS (Lambda, S3, ECR, ECS, VPC, App Mesh, CloudWatch, SDK, CDK, CloudFormation), Heroku, DigitalOcean

Frameworks

Node, Express, React/Redux, Sinatra

Other Technologies

PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Linux, HTTP, REST APIs, Git/GitHub, Docker, HTML/CSS, NGINX

EXPERIENCE

2022 - present

Co-creator, Software Engineer, Chimera - chimera-deploy.dev *⊘*

- Researched, designed, prototyped and implemented Chimera, a tool for performing automated canary deployments of microservices hosted on AWS Elastic Container Service using AWS App Mesh for inter-service communication
- Utilized AWS CloudWatch and Prometheus to monitor metrics related to deployment
- Designed and implemented an Express backend that can be used to create and configure AWS resources
- Utilized server sent events to pass live updates and metrics to a user interface
- Designed and implemented a locally-hosted React/Redux frontend to configure and begin deployments
- Presented a live tech-talk about Chimera
- Authored a comprehensive technical case study

2020 - 2022

Full-Stack Web Developer, Self-employed

- Developed open-source software using Node.js, Express, Sinatra, PostgreSQL, React/Redux, vanilla JavaScript, HTML, and CSS
- Meridian a deep space object tracker built with React, PostgreSQL, MongoDB and deployed on a DigitalOcean Droplet.
- Chip8-js a chip-8 interpreter for the browser built with JavaScript
- SchemeEdit a browser based editor for the Scheme programming language built with JavaScript
- Requesto Webhook and HTTP request visualizer for viewing and debugging network communication built using Node, PostgreSQL, and MongoDB.

2017 - 2020

Reports Specialist, Charter Communications

• Received the Charter Gold award in 2019, an annual recognition of the top performers across the organization

EDUCATION

2020 - 2022

Launch School

Multi-year, full-stack software engineering curriculum emphasizing mastery of programming fundamentals and problem-solving

2015

BS in Computer Information Technology, Southern New Hampshire University